以前在那些即将死去的人身上......
Previously on
Those About to Die...
如果那个伤痕累累的大个子来了，你们中的一个人会跟着他
If the big, scarred man
comes, one of you follows him
另一个来找我。
and the other one
comes to find me.
你的兄弟姐妹正在为他们的生命而战，
Your brother and sister
are fighting for their lives,
你说得好像这是一次伟大的冒险？
and you talk as if this is
some great adventure?
维斯塔尔处女，
The Vestal Virgins,
罗马永恒之火的守护者。
guardians of
Rome's eternal flame.
你能帮我吗？
Could you help me?
我的母亲会不会为她的女儿流泪，就像你为你的女儿流泪一样。
Would that my mother had had tears
for her daughter, as you do for yours.
而对于我们的家庭来说，
And for our family,
我们会烧毁整个该死的帝国。
we'll burn down the
entire fucking empire.
找掩护。
Take cover.
关门。
Close the door.
拿到粗麻布！迅速！
Get the burlap! Quickly!
加夫罗斯。
Gavros.
天蝎座，回来吧。
Scorpus, come back.
你叫什么名字？
What is your name?
西娜。
Xena.
维苏威火山爆发了。
Vesuvius has erupted.
风吹起了灰烬云
The winds have
carried the ash cloud
超过100个联赛，横跨罗马及其他地区的大部分地区。
over 100 leagues across
much of Rome and beyond.
庞贝城和赫库兰尼姆仅此而已。
Pompeii and
Herculaneum and no more.
幸存者？
Survivors?
十五人，也许是18,000人，前往罗马。
Fifteen, perhaps 18,000,
making their way to Rome.
几艘船有时间扬帆，
A few ships had
time to raise sail,
他们带着几百名幸存者抵达奥斯蒂亚。
they're arriving at Ostia
with a few hundred survivors.
我们将派出一批禁卫军
We'll send a cohort
of Praetorians
在亚壁古道上与那些人会面。
to meet those on the Appian Way.
食物、医生、衣服。
Food, physicians, clothing.
还有更多。
There's more.
更 糟。
Worse.
维斯塔的火焰已经熄灭了。
The vestal flame has gone out.
来自整个罗马的无声厄运。
A silent doom from all of Rome.
它无人看管......
It was unattended...
它已经被重新点燃，Vestal Matron
It has been reignited
and the Vestal Matron
被鞭打，她的尸体挂在赎罪中。
has been flogged, her
corpse hangs in atonement.
设置营地。收集食物。
Set encampments. Gather food.
传出消息，罗马将为有需要的人敞开大门。
Send word that Rome will
open her gates for those in need.
立即。
At once.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
那个角斗士，努米底亚人，
That gladiator, the Numidian,
当我给他奖金时，
when I was giving
him his prize money,
他正要从我的一名警卫手中抢过一把短剑。
he was moving to grab a
gladius from one of my guards.
他要杀了我。
He was going to kill me.
你能想象吗？
Can you imagine?
像我这样有 auctoritas 和 gravitas 的人，
A man of auctoritas and
gravitas such as myself,
被老鼠杀死了。
killed by a mouse.
踩在他身上。
Step on him.
我认为 Flamma 会做踩踏。
I think Flamma
will do the stepping.
他复仇的时机已经成熟。
He's ripe for revenge.
那将是最有趣的
That would be the
most entertaining
粉碎小生物的方式。
way to crush
the little creature.
嘿！
Hey!
-嘿！-这是怎么回事？
- Hey!
- What's going on?
退后。退后。
Stay back. Stay back.
但是他做了什么？
But what has he done?
他激发了图密善的敌意。
He's excited the
animus of Domitian.
Flamma 将进行二番战，赢得 Kwame
There will be a rematch
for Flamma, earning Kwame
一种特殊的死亡。
a special death.
-把他带走。-你这个混蛋！
- Take him away.
- You bastard!
只有水。没有食物。
Water only. No food.
这减轻了他的一些战斗力。
This takes some of
the fight out of him.
酒。
Wine.
刚从高卢收到。
Just received from Gaul.
看。。。
Look...
这是我们的儿子。
it's our son.
和他父亲一样帅气。
As handsome as his father.
有成千上万的难民从庞贝城涌入，
There's thousands of refugees
pouring in from Pompeii,
更多在途中。
more en route.
提多答应给他们住房和食物。
Titus has promised
them housing and food.
这是我们一直在等待的时刻。
It's the moment
we've been waiting for.
外！
Out!
我和蒂莉亚和索罗谈过
I spoke with Tilia and Soro
以及参议院的其他一些围栏保姆。
and some of the other
fence-sitters in the Senate.
他们在摇摆不定。
They're wavering.
好吧，我们问了很多。
Well, we're asking
a lot of them.
他们的家庭和财富都受到了影响
Their families and
fortunes have suffered
在四帝之年。
in the Year of the
Four Emperors.
这对皇帝来说是一场赌博
And it is a gamble
for an Emperor
死去，被你取代。
to die and be replaced by you.
参议院看到提图斯耗尽了国库，这很有帮助。
It helps that the Senate sees
Titus draining the Treasury.
他们明天晚上会秘密会面，
They're meeting
tomorrow night, in secret,
听我说。
to listen to me.
他不在这里。
He is not here.
这是紧急的。
It is urgent.
妹妹！
Little sister!
Tenax，你现在在这里工作吗？
Tenax has you working here now?
是的，但现在被释放了。
Yes, but freed now.
茱拉，茱拉，我有机会买到她的自由。
Jula, Jula, I had the
chance to buy her freedom.
我保证我会为你做同样的事情。
I promise I'll do
the same for you.
我为你感到高兴。
I am so happy for you.
我希望是你被释放了。
I wish it had been
you who was freed.
你有什么要给我的吗？
Do you have something for me?
- 全部？-是的。
- All of them?
- Yes.
干的好。去。
Well done. Go.
我们离开太久了。
We've been away too long.
她说的对。我需要在我的情妇注意到之前回来。
She's right. I need to get back
before my mistress notices.
去。注意安全。
Go. Be safe.
以为是这样。
Think it was this way.
对不起。
Excuse me.
我们迷失了方向。
We've lost our way.
很容易做到。
Easy to do.
但我很荣幸能帮助你。
But I would be
honored to help you.
我必须去Esquiline。
I have to go to the Esquiline.
我可以告诉你。跟我来。
I can show you. Follow me.
这是出路。向左。
This is the way
out. To the left.
谢谢。
Thank you.
晚上的街道已经够危险的了。
The streets are
dangerous enough at night.
我会陪你一起去的。
I will accompany you.
请做。
Please do.
我们走吧。
Let's go.
我会确保她安全回家。
I'll see to it that she
gets home safely.
不要占便宜。
Do not take advantage.
这边。
This way.
所以，朱拉，你最终变成了奴隶......
And so, Jula, you ended
up becoming a slave...
在马苏斯领事的家里。
In the house of Consul Marsus.
你可以一个人出去吗？
And you can go out alone?
我可以，但我必须小心。
I can, but I have to be careful.
跟我说说你的兄弟们吧。
Tell me about your brothers.
他们听起来像是少数。
They sound like a handful.
想象一下与他们共用一个房间......
Imagine sharing
the room with them...
至少在家里，我们有自己的空间。
At least at home,
we had our space.
连绵起伏的丘陵，茂密的草，你可以在里面游泳。
Rolling hills, grass so
thick, you could swim in it.
我可以想象你的马喜欢它。
I can imagine your
horses loved it.
嗯。
Hmm.
我最近有这种感觉。
I have had this feeling of late.
我再也不会踏上我的祖国了。
That I will never set foot
in my homeland again.
这种感觉我很清楚。
That is a feeling I know well.
谢谢你带我走，Elia。
Thank you for walking me, Elia.
我能再见到你吗？
Can I see you again?
或。
Maybe.
提图斯·弗拉维乌斯·多米提亚努斯，一个多才多艺的人，
Titus Flavius Domitianus,
a man of many talents,
其中最重要的是惹恼了你的兄弟。
not least of which is
pissing off your brother.
或者你是说洗劫耶路撒冷是帕苏斯的主意？
Or are you saying that the sacking
of Jerusalem was Passus' idea?
我为此感到自豪。
I am rather proud of it.
不要用我哥哥的肮脏名字来称呼我。
And don't call me by
my brother's filthy name.
图密善会做的。
Domitian will do.
我知道你如何才能赢得你哥哥的信任
I know how you can
win your brother's trust
并让我们的派系恢复运行。
and get our faction
back up and running.
我听着呢。
I'm listening.
马苏斯召集了参议院会议。
Marsus has convened
a meeting of the Senate.
暗。
In secret.
所以，我猛扑过去，把他们都逮捕了，然后......
So, I swoop in,
arrest them all and...
拯救皇帝。
save the Emperor.
你只需要在那里。
You just need to be there.
看到这一切，让他们用自己的话吊死自己。
See it all and let them hang
themselves on their own words.
还有另一批难民正在前往罗马的途中。
There's another group of
refugees en route to Rome.
在Martius校园的公寓里准备一个营地。
Prepare an encampment on
the flats of Campus Martius.
粮食，木柴，城市警卫。
Provisions, firewood,
urban guards.
快点吧，我很忙。
Let's make it quick, I'm busy.
如果你对我多一点尊重，我可以更好地为你服务
I could serve you better if you
treated me with more respect
比克拉克或客户的。
than that of a
clark or a client.
这是一种习惯。
It's a habit.
在指挥帐篷里呆了太多天。
Too many days in a command tent.
外。
Out.
你和我一样处于危险之中。
You are in jeopardy, as am I.
为了保护我们俩，
In order to protect us both,
我需要你暂停我的禁闭。
I need you to suspend
my confinement.
哥哥。
Brother.
这就是我说的那个人。
This is the man I spoke of.
我的客户，Tenax。
My client, Tenax.
这样，凯撒。
This way, Caesar.
你们两个，和我一起。
You two, with me.
你在令人不安的时刻勇敢地度过了夜晚。我感谢你。
You brave the night in
troubling times. I thank you.
几个世纪以来，我们的家庭
For centuries, our families
他们负责保护我们心爱的城市和帝国
have been charged with protecting
our beloved city and Empire
来自那些会激怒众神的人。
from those who
would anger the Gods.
然而，现在他们可怕的判决从天而降。
Yet now their terrible verdict
rains down from the sky.
我们都知道，随着维斯塔尔火焰的熄灭，
And we all know, that with
the Vestal flame extinguished,
我们不再受到灶神星和众神的保护，
we are no longer protected
by Vesta and the Gods,
这可能真的是时代的终结。
and this could truly
be the end of times.
所以我问自己，弟兄们，发生了什么变化
So I ask myself, brothers,
what has changed
从过去的快乐日子开始？
since the happy
days of the past?
我找不到其他答案，只能......
And I can find no
other answer but...
我们有一位新皇帝。
that we have a new Emperor.
轻踩，领事。
Tread lightly, Consul.
参议员，我们今天都轻装上阵，
We all tread lightly
today, Senator,
在灰烬上！
on ashes!
就想想皇帝吧
Just consider an Emperor
谁偏爱国家而不是罗马本身，
who favors the country
over Rome itself,
谁和一个异教徒的犹太女王躺在一起。
and who lies with a
heretic Judean Queen.
难怪众神选择埋葬我们！
No wonder the Gods
have chosen to bury us!
但是他已经抛弃了他的犹太女王，
But he has discarded
his Judean Queen,
并娶了一个罗马妻子。
and taken a Roman wife.
他娶了一个罗马妻子只会进一步加重他的罪行，
His taking a Roman wife only
further compounds his crime,
对于犹太毒蛇
for the Judean viper
仍然与他同床共枕
still shares his bed
并在他耳边嘶嘶作响。
and hisses her
poison in his ear.
希伯来神喜悦罗马跪下。
The Hebrew God delights
as Rome sinks to her knees.
那么罗马人呢？
And what of the Roman people?
我们的员工？
Our People?
我们的客户？
Our clients?
我们的神圣职责？
Our sacred duty?
我们的人睡在下水道里
Our people sleep in the sewer
而提多打开了闸门
while Titus opens
the flood gates
成千上万的难民。
to thousands of refugees.
他给这些陌生人喂奶
He suckles these strangers
并把剩下的钱花在花哨的纪念碑上
and spends what's left on
garish monuments to himself
和他的家人，
and his family,
而罗马人民却在挨饿！
while the people of Rome starve!
羞耻！
Shame!
没有人质疑变革的必要性。
No one questions
the need for change.
唯一的问题是，它能成功吗？
The only question
is, can it succeed?
它可以而且必须。
It can and it must.
我向你们保证，遥远的军团，
I assure you, the
distant legions,
近身卫兵，罗马人民，
the close guards,
the people of Rome,
众神自己也会为这种变化鼓掌！
and the Gods themselves
will applaud the change!
- 尼禄的命运！- 尼禄的命运！
- The fate of Nero!
马苏斯领事，
Consul Marsus,
参议员托雷尔和塞普尔修斯，都是叛徒！
Senators Torel and
Sepulcius, traitors all!
逮捕他们。
Arrest them.
主。
Lord.
众神恳求我们采取行动，
The Gods beseech us to act,
现在是时候了。
and the time is now.
执政官马尔苏斯、参议员托雷尔和塞普尔修斯
The Consul Marsus, the
Senators Torel and Sepulcius
特此以叛国罪被捕。
are hereby arrested for treason.
抓住他！
Take him!
还有他。
And him.
拿走他们！
Take them!
和我在一起。
With me.
所以你为蓝军和白军开车？
So you drove for the
Blues and the Whites?
11个第一。
Eleven firsts.
哇。
Wow.
发生了什么事？
What happened?
酒。。。和高尚的生活。
Wine... and high living.
天蝎座就是这样做的。他仍然开车。
Scorpus does
that. He still drives.
就是这样，还有更多。
It was that and more.
把一个人放在战车上需要很多，
Takes a lot to put
a man in a chariot,
更让他放弃。
and even more
for him to give it up.
那么，你为什么要这样做？
So, why did you?
我开始参加比赛是因为马匹。
I started racing
because of the horses.
像你一样，
Like you,
我能感觉到他们。
I can feel them.
但赛车是不同的。
But racing is different.
四匹马的比赛是自杀，你......以某种方式生存。
A four-horse race is a
suicide you... somehow survive.
我看到六个朋友死在赛道上，
I saw half-a-dozen
friends die on the track,
我自己也勉强避免了死亡
and I barely
avoided death myself
比这更多的次数。
more times than that.
然后，有一天我离开了那条轨道，我完成了。
And then, one day I walked
off that track, and I was done.
一旦你开始思考死亡，
Once you start
thinking about death,
结束了。
it's over.
我的兄弟们都想参加比赛。
My brothers both want to race.
你担心他们。
You worry about them.
生活很少会按照你期望的方式进行。
Life rarely goes
the way you expect.
嘘。这是给你的。
Psst. This is for you.
只是一会儿。
Just a short while.
哥哥。
Brother.
我担心我会空着肚子死去。
I feared I was to die
on an empty stomach.
皇帝的弟弟
The Emperor's brother
似乎对你的死感兴趣。
seems to have an
interest in your death.
这种感觉是相互的，兄弟。
The feeling is mutual, brother.
但我认为他会先如愿以偿。
But I think he will
get his wish first.
观众想要二番战。
The crowd would like a rematch.
他们带着复仇的兴奋。
They carry the
excitement of revenge.
多少次在战斗前夕，
How many times
on the eve of battle,
你与死亡和平相处了吗？
did you make your
peace with death?
太多了，数不清。
Too many to count.
每一次，你都欺骗了死亡。
And each time,
you cheated death.
在战斗中，我的人民以我们的咆哮而闻名
In battle, my people
are known for our roar
当我们冲锋时，吓唬我们的敌人。
as we charge,
terrifying our enemy.
在我们奔向他们的刀剑和盾牌之前，
Before we run at their
swords and shields,
我们低声恳求死亡。
we whisper a quiet
entreaty to death.
死神啊，如果你愿意，就带我去吧，
Take me if you will, O Death,
但让我活着不是更好吗
but is it not better
to let me live
并通过杀人来服侍你？
and serve you by killing others?
大胆的词语。
Bold words.
亲自向死神提出交易。
Offering a deal
to Death himself.
她自己。
Herself.
死亡是一个女人。
Death is a woman.
到目前为止，她一直在听我的话。
She has so far listened to me.
哈莉娅，也许她会听你的。
Halja, perhaps she
will listen to you.
我想她太爱弗拉玛了，救不了我，兄弟。
I think she is too in love with
Flamma to save me, brother.
我什么时候死？
When do I die?
五天。
Five days.
我的朋友给我带来了酒。
And my friend brings me wine.
短暂的一生仍然可以是美好的生活。
A short life can
still be a good life.
我欠你的债，兄弟。
I am in your debt, brother.
我只担心你的安全，就像我担心父亲的安全一样。
I worry only for your
safety, as I did Father's.
你认为参议院会如何反应？
How do you think
the Senate will react?
他们会看的。
They'll watch.
并等待暴徒的反应。
And wait for the
reaction of the mob.
呵呵，那你有什么建议？
Huh, so what do you suggest?
增加谷物。
Increase the grain dole.
波尔图？告诉我。
Porto? Tell me.
我们的粮食储备足以使它翻倍。
We have grain stores
enough to double it.
然后这样做。
Then do so.
还有什么？
What else?
将首届运动会从50天增加到100天。
Increase the Inaugural Games
from fifty days to a hundred.
并带回人民的英雄。
And bring back
the people's hero.
让天蝎座再次为黄金派系而战。
Let Scorpus race again
for the Gold Faction.
这是非常明智的。
That's very wise.
派系主主在他们的感情中取代了我，
The faction owners have
replaced me in their affection,
所以我要把他们换成暴徒。
so I shall replace
them in the mob's.
黄金派系将恢复。
The Gold faction
will be reinstated.
你有我的话。
You have my word.
我哥哥答应了我
My brother has granted me
另一个为他服务的机会。
another opportunity
to serve him.
我将组织增加的首届运动会
I am to organize the
increased Inaugural Games
我们的弗拉维安圆形剧场。
of our Flavian Amphitheater.
赌注的巨额将是你喜欢的。
The enormity of the
wagers will be to your liking.
毫无疑问。
No doubt.
但谁将成为这些游戏的主人呢？
But who will be
master of these games?
- 帕苏斯？- 他有经验。
- Passus?
- He has experience.
各派系的礼貌和对他们的尊重。
Courtesy of the factions
and beholden to them.
你还有别的建议吗？
You have another suggestion?
那我呢？
What about me?
你雄心勃勃。
You are ambitious.
我对你毫不隐瞒。
I've made no secret
of that with you.
你确实有一定的才能。
You do have certain talents.
但娱乐艺术是其中之一吗？
But is the art of
entertainment one of them?
恕我直言，殿下......
With all due respect,
Your Highness...
你太高了
you are too far
above the lower order
知道他们真正想要什么。
to know what they really want.
我知道，因为我是他们中的一员。
I know, because I'm one of them.
我感受到了他们的饥饿，
I have felt their hunger,
并生活在他们的污秽中。
and lived in their filth.
我知道他们害怕什么，我知道他们渴望什么，
I know what they fear,
and I know what they crave,
我可以设计出满足这种渴望的娱乐方式。
and I can devise entertainment
that will feed that craving.
它们比你想象的更基础。
They're more base
than you can imagine.
很好，一个测试。
Very well, a test.
让我们看看你如何处决叛徒。
Let's see how you do with
the execution of the traitors.
当你这样做时，
And while you do so,
让斯科普斯回到我的一辆黄金战车上。
get Scorpus back in one
of my Golden chariots.
哎呀！哎呀！
Hyah! Hyah!
哎呀！
Hyah!
你可以的！加油！
You can do it! Come on!
天蝎座！天蝎座！天蝎座！
Scorpus! Scorpus! Scorpus!
-哦！是天蝎座！-女士 们。
- Oh! It's Scorpus!
- Ladies.
你被逮捕了。
You are under arrest.
不。
No.
我是天蝎座，一个派系的首席战车手。
I'm Scorpus, lead
charioteer of a faction.
把你的手拿开。
Get your hands off me.
哎呀！你听着。我是伟大的天蝎座。
Oi! You listen. I am
The Great Scorpus.
不是你的动物之一。
Not one of your animals.
皇帝会听到的！
The Emperor will hear of this!
你这样对我。
You did this to me.
你这头猪。
You pig.
好吧，你和天蝎座玩得很开心。
Well, you had your
fun with Scorpus.
现在，让他出去。
Now, let him out.
您因非法博彩而被捕。
You were arrested
for illegal betting.
非法投注？
Illegal betting?
这是来自你们这样的人的笑话。是的？
It's a joke coming from
the likes of you. Yes?
对我来说很有趣，我的朋友，
Funny for me, my friend,
不是真的适合你。
not really for you.
但是，为了我们的旧友谊，
But, for the sake
of our old friendship,
我可能会结束这一切，
I could probably end this,
如果你只是简单地签回黄金派系。
if you simply sign back
to the Gold Faction.
哦，看在他妈的份上，天蝎座。
Oh, for fuck sake's, Scorpus.
你拥有黄金派系25%的股份。
You own 25% of the Gold faction.
它值十倍......一百倍以上
It's worth ten times... a
hundred times more than
莱托付给你的可怜的 600,000 美元！
the measly 600,000
that Leto's paying you!
去他妈的自己。
Go fuck yourself.
等。等！
Wait. Wait!
我会为金牌而战，
I will drive for the Gold,
但你再也不叫我朋友了。
but you don't ever
call me a friend again.
不错的选择...
Good choice...
我的朋友。
my friend.
嘿！
Hey!
嘿，你放我出去，你这个小混蛋！
Hey, you let me
out, you little shit!
为灶神星祈祷。
A prayer for Vesta.
哦，永恒炉膛的女神。
Oh Goddess of
the eternal hearth.
你的祷告会被垂听。
Your prayer will be heard.
科妮莉亚。看看你
Cornelia. Look at you,
处女座维斯塔利斯千里马！
Virgo Vestalis Maxima!
维斯塔尔酋长。
Chief Vestal.
你父亲和我为你的提升而欢欣鼓舞。
Your father and I
rejoice at your elevation.
一个女人被棍棒和鞭打致死，
A woman clubbed
and flogged to death,
因为维斯塔大火熄灭了。
because the vestal
fires went out.
那是你骄傲的源泉吗？
That is a source of your pride?
那么，这次会议是关于什么的呢？
So, what is this meeting about?
- 你可能没有听说过... - 维斯塔尔人听到了一切。
- You may not have heard...
- The Vestals hear everything.
作为 Vestal Matron，您为众神代言。
As Vestal Matron,
you speak for the Gods.
如果我们一起去皇帝面前
If we go before the
Emperor together
- 并恳求你父亲的性命...... - 不。
- and plead for your father's life...
- No.
Cornelia，你的父亲需要你。
Cornelia, your father needs you.
他不需要我，
He did not need me,
当他把我关在这个金笼子里将近 30 年时。
when he condemned me to this
golden cage for nearly 30 years.
我们给了你与众神交流的机会。
We gave you opportunity
to commune with the Gods.
我从来没有听说过。一次都没有！
I've never heard them. Not once!
你把我关在这监狱里，
You placed me in this prison,
你派我来这里，不是为了我的利益，
you sent me here,
not for my benefit,
但为了你自己和我兄弟的荣耀。
but for your own glory
and that of my brother.
放弃你是我的责任，
It was my duty to give you up,
现在，这是你的职责
and now, it is your duty
帮助拯救你的父亲
to help save your father
从Tarpeian岩石上扔下来。
from being thrown
off the Tarpeian rock.
如果可以的话，我会帮忙把他推开。
I would help push
him off if I could.
不要说这样的话。
Do not say such a thing.
你是他的女儿。
You are his daughter.
我是维斯塔处女。
I'm a Vestal Virgin.
我不再是他的女儿，
I am no longer his daughter,
或你的。
or yours.
科妮莉亚！
Cornelia!
我求求你了。
I beg of you.
你收到我的信了吗？
Did you get my letter?
我明白你有多爱
I understand how much you love
你的西班牙马...
your Spanish horses...
但请告诉我你在来之前去过浴场。
but please tell me you visited
the baths before coming.
-总是。- “总是，”他说。
- Always.
- "Always," he says.
哦。你确实去洗澡了。
Oh. You did go to the baths.
你的话掩盖了真相。
Your words hide the truth.
我知道你有多喜欢马厩的味道。
I know how much you
love the smell of stables.
哦。。。从不。
Oh... never.
我想把你从这里偷走。
I want to steal you
away from here.
然后你会看到我被钉在十字架上。
Then you would see
me nailed to the cross.
马苏斯被关在牢房里。
Marsus is in a cell.
他不能再伤害你了。
He can no longer harm you.
我的情妇呢？
What about my mistress?
我们会买到你的自由。
We'll buy your freedom.
用什么？
With what?
我有我的工资和一小部分梭哈费。
I have my wages and the
small portion of the stud fees.
在几场胜利之后，这将是值得的。
After a few wins, it
will be worth something.
三千塞斯特斯？
Three thousand sesterces?
因为那是她为我付出的代价。
Because that is
what she paid for me.
我相信
I believe
如果你有钱，你会救我。
if you had the money,
you would save me.
朱拉，停下。
Jula, stop.
否则，我不想停下来。
Otherwise, I won't want to stop.
如果我不想停下来怎么办？
What if I don't want to stop?
我担心......
I feared...
我的第一次
my first time
会和...
would be with...
我希望它和你在一起。
I want it to be
with you instead.
至少我知道它应该是什么感觉。
At least I know
how it should feel.
我也不知道应该有什么感觉。
I don't know how
it should feel either.
然后。。。
Then...
让我们一起发现它。
let us discover it together.
是否确定？
Are you sure?
我敢肯定。
I am sure.
在我看来，它们是一样的。
They look the same to me.
是的。看起来是这样，
Yes. It would appear so,
但它们要轻得多。
but they're much, much lighter.
更难驾驶，但速度要快得多。
More difficult to
drive, but much faster.
那我的付款呢？
And what about my payment?
我们稍后再谈钱。
Let's talk about money later.
这是怎麽？
What is this?
我该怎么办？
What am I supposed
to do with this?
哦。
Oh.
批准。
Approved.
- 一切都好吗？- 都很好。
- All good?
- All good.
天蝎座！天蝎座！天蝎座！
Scorpus! Scorpus! Scorpus!
来吧，快点！
Come on, faster!
天蝎座再次出手。
Scorpus makes his move again.
这可能是他本周的第三场胜利。
Could be his third
victory this week.
天蝎座！天蝎座！天蝎座！
Scorpus! Scorpus! Scorpus!
你是对的，图密善。
You were right, Domitian.
暴民内容，
The mob content,
参议院畏缩不前。
and the Senate cowed.
- 愿我们的血液占上风。- 直到罗马本身沦陷。
- May our blood prevail.
- Till Rome itself falls.
去！去！
Go! Go!
哦，亲爱的！
Oh, dear!
你去哪儿？
Where are you going?
比赛还没有结束。
The race is not finished.
我的司机遭遇了海难。我为什么要留下来？
My drivers shipwrecked.
Why should I stay?
我开始理解人群对这个天蝎座的热爱。
I'm beginning to understand
the crowd's love for this Scorpus.
是的！
Yes!
天蝎座！天蝎座！天蝎座！
Scorpus! Scorpus! Scorpus!
啊，胜利的派系老板！
Ah, the victorious
faction owner!
我有一个问题：
I have a question:
投注总是在比赛开始前停止？
the betting is always
stopped before the race starts?
-答案是肯定的。-为什么？
- Of course.
- Why?
一直都是这样。
It's always been done that way.
这就是法律。
That's the law.
你总是遵守法律吗？
Do you always follow the law?
你把钱留在桌子上，
You are leaving
money on the table,
很多。
lots of it.
在努米底亚，有赛马、斗鸡、摔跤、
In Numidia, with horse
racing, cock fighting, wrestling,
投注贯穿整场比赛。
the betting goes
for the whole match.
如果你被抓住了怎么办？
And what if you get caught?
违法的关键是不要这样做。
The key to breaking
the law is not to.
我们所要做的就是改变投注系统。
All we have to do is
change the betting system.
我们如何做到这一点，并接受新的赌注？
And how do we do that,
and take the new bets?
我们把你的孩子放在看台上。
We put your kids in the stands.
嗯。
Hmm.
“恭喜你。
"Congratulations.
“你把你的黄金派系找回来了。
"You have your
Gold Faction back.
“你的奖金，
"Your winnings,
“否则你的孩子会继续死去，
"or your boys will
continue to die,
“你的秘密将不再是秘密。
"and your secret will
be a secret no more.
“这永远不会结束。
"This will never end.
“除非你结束它。”
"Unless you end it."
Tenax，有人想和你谈谈。
Tenax, somebody
wants to speak with you.
他想和你开会。
He wants a conference with you.
告诉他我早上第一件事就是去那里。
Tell him I'll be there
first thing in the morning.
他在等你，
He's waiting for you,
现在。
now.
Tenax 来了。
Tenax is here.
对不起，兄弟，我的一个客户。
Excuse me, brother,
one of my clients.
外！
Out!
我以为我会亲自领取我的奖金。
I thought I would collect
my winnings in person.
来了，多米纳斯。
Coming, Dominus.
这些大赌注都是靠信用进行的。
These big bets
are made on credit.
我们必须等待贵族偿还债务。
We have to wait for the
patricians to pay their debts.
明天把你欠的钱给我。
Bring me what you owe tomorrow.
理解？
Understood?
你！你偷了我的司机。
You! You stole my driver.
你必须和天蝎座谈谈。
You'll have to talk
to Scorpus about that.
天蝎座达成了交易。
Scorpus made a deal.
他现在属于白派。
He belongs to the
White Faction now.
他似乎不这么认为。
He doesn't seem to think so.
如果你想要忠诚，你应该给你的男人更多的钱。
If you want loyalty, you
should pay your men more.
你这个该死的暴发户！
You fucking upstart!
我希望他回来。
I want him back.
你们，你们所有人，
You, all of you,
你认为众神膏你来领导吗？
you think the Gods have
anointed you to lead?
你错了。
You're wrong.
你的位置和你杀死的那些人一样脆弱
Your positions are as fragile
as those the men you killed
要到达你所在的位置，现在让开。
to get to where you
are, now step aside.
还是我应该打电话给警卫？
Or should I call the guards?
我是个大忙人。
I'm a busy man.
谢谢你，参议员。
Thank you, Senator.
特纳克斯！你要走了吗
Tenax! Are you
just going to leave
从今天开始不给我我的份额？
without giving me
my share from today?
我很着急。
I'm in a hurry.
嘿，你怎么了？
Hey, what is wrong with you?
- 你喝醉了？-是的，我是。
- You're drunk?
- Yes, I am.
我需要我的钱。我有一场胜利的狂欢要付出代价。
And I need my money. I
have a victory orgy to pay for.
赊账。
Have it on credit.
我赢了。
I won.
我们的派系赢了。
Our faction won.
来吧，天蝎座必须得到报酬！
Come on, Scorpus must be paid!
当我拥有它时。
When I have it.
那辆购物车里有什么？
What is in that cart?
我不想听到你的任何其他消息，
I don't want to hear
anything else from you,
直到我有钱。
until I have my money.
我想要我的钱！
I want my money!
我想要我的钱。
I want my money.
-什么？-还没有。
- Anything?
- Not yet.
我已经按照你的要求回到了伊德斯。
I have returned on the
Ides as you requested.
你能帮我吗？
Would you help me?
有一个人，
There's a man,
特纳克斯。
Tenax.
一个罪犯。
A criminal.
你认识他吗？
Do you know him?
是的。
Yes.
他把我的大女儿当奴隶。
He owned my eldest
daughter as a slave.
我为她买了自由，
I bought her freedom,
现在她和我为他工作。
and now she and I work for him.
他带着他罪行的恶臭。
He carries the
stench of his crimes.
你也被那股恶臭玷污了。
You are tainted
by that stench, too.
我只为我的孩子做这件事。
I only do it for my children.
然而，你却试图欺骗我
And yet, you
sought to deceive me
用我来解救你的女儿。
and use me to
free your daughter.
- 不，不，不... - 你假设
- No, no, no...
- You assumed
我对父母怀有恶意，
I bear ill will
toward my parents,
你认为你可以使用它
and you thought
you could use that
将您的孩子从他们手中解放出来。
to free your child from them.
是的。
Yes.
关于罗马，你还有很多东西需要学习
There's much you still
need to learn of Rome
和 Vestals。
and the Vestals.
我屬於這座城市，而不是我父親。
I belong to this
city, not to my father.
他密谋破坏神圣的秩序，必须死。
He conspired to break the
divine order, and must die.
你不配为我代祷。
You are not worthy
of my intercession.
不，拜托。我的女儿，她是无辜的，
No, please. My daughter,
she's an innocent,
她值得你保护。
she's worthy of your protection.
只有罗马值得我保护。
Only Rome is worthy
of my protection.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
黑暗的一天。
A dark day.
同意。
Agreed.
目前。
At the moment.
那是什么样子？
What is that look?
我正在重新考虑我与你的关系。
I'm reconsidering my
association with you.
尼卡。妮卡，醒醒！
Nica. Nica, wake up!
你留在这里！
You stay here!
特纳克斯！特纳克斯！
Tenax! Tenax!
脸上有疤痕的大个子。
Big man with scars on his face.
锁上门。
Lock the door.
- 达契亚在哪里？-不知道。
- Where's Dacia?
- No idea.
快 点。
Hurry.
在这里等候。
Wait here.
放下刀。
Drop the knife.
你应该付给你的男人更多的钱。
You should pay your men more.
你想活下去吗？
You want to live?
刀，
The knife,
慢慢移动
move it slowly
到你虚弱的手上。把它传给我，下手。
to your weak hand.
Pass it to me, underhand.
如果你想做某事，就自己做。
If you want something
done, do it yourself.
现在，我已经从你那里夺走了一切，
Now, that I've taken
everything from you,
我要杀了你。
I'm going to kill you.
很好，你从与暴徒和低等人的战斗中学到了东西。
Good, you learned from
fighting thugs and low-lifes.
我从地球上最伟大的军队中战斗中学到了东西。
I learned from fighting in the
greatest army on this Earth.
昆图斯。
Quintus.
你只是一个发牢骚的小弱者。
You're just a
whiny little weakling.
现在，我要离开你，就像你离开我一样。
Now, I'll leave
you, as you left me.
在我们杀死我们的主人之前，
Before we killed our master,
他向我透露了他最黑暗的秘密。
he revealed his
darkest secret to me.
因为他的妻子拥有一个种马场，
Because his wife
owned a stud farm,
他把你当作奴隶藏在她的眼皮底下。
he hid you as a slave
right under her nose.
当你在地狱里烤的时候，
While you roast in hell,
想想看。
think about this.
他是你的父亲！
He was your father!
没错。贵族的血液流淌在你身上。
That's right. Patrician
blood runs through you.
再见了，小昆图斯。
Farewell, little Quintus.